<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tiziano De Matteis</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Tiziano De Matteis</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Tiziano De Matteis</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Softwares</title>
      <link>/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/software/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;program-committee&#34;&gt;Program Committee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2025, USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2025, IEEE International Parallel &amp;amp; Distributed Processing Symposium (IPDPS)  – Monitoring track&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2024, International Symposium on High-Level Parallel Programming and Applications (HLPP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2024, Workshop on Irregular Applications: Architectures and Algorithms (IA3 – co-located with Supercomputing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2024, ACM Symposium on  High-Performance Parallel and Distributed Computing (HPDC) - Poster session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2024, International Conference on Parallel Processing (ICPP) - ”Software” track&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2024, ICT.Open 2024 - CompSys track&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2023, IEEE International Symposium on Cluster, Cloud and Internet Computing (CCGrid 2023) – “Software Systems and Platforms” track&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2023, Supercomputing (SC) - “Post-Moore Computing” track&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2023, IEEE  International Conference on High Performance Computing, Data, and Analytics (HiPC) – “High-Performance Computing – System Software” track&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022, Supercomputing (SC) – Artifact Evaluation Committee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2021, ACM International Conference on Architectural Support for Programming Languages and Operating Systems (ASPLOS ) – Artifact Evaluation Committee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2021, Supercomputing (SC) – Artifact Evaluation Committee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020,  International Conference on High Performance Computing &amp;amp; Simulation (HPCS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020,  IARIA International Conference on Advanced Communications and Computation (INFOCOMP 2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019,  International Conference on High Performance Computing &amp;amp; Simulation (HPCS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024, Co-Organizer of the Workshop on Hot Topics in Cloud Computing Performance (HotCloudPerf 2024) – Co-located at ICPE 2024&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019, Publicity and Web Chair for the Autonomic Solutions for Parallel and Distributed Data Stream Processing (Auto-DaSP 2019) workshop – Co-located at Europar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018, Publicity and Web Chair for the Autonomic Solutions for Parallel and Distributed Data Stream Processing (Auto-DaSP) workshop – Co-located at Europar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018, Local Chair at the 24th International European Conference on Parallel and Distributed Computing (Europar 2018) –  “Theory and Algorithms for Parallel Computation and Networking” track&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017, Program Chair of the Special Session in “Smart Home and E-Health to improve the Quality of Life” at the 3rd EAI International Conference on Smart Objects and Technologies for Social Good (GoodTechs 2017)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;theses-and-projects&#34;&gt;Theses and Projects&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My research interests are in abstractions, systems, and tools for &lt;strong&gt;High-Performance Computing (HPC)&lt;/strong&gt;. More specifically, I work on accelerators such as &lt;em&gt;Spatial/Dataflow Devices&lt;/em&gt; (e.g., FPGAs – Field Programmable Gate Arrays –, CGRAs, Machine Learning Accelerators) and &lt;em&gt;GPUs&lt;/em&gt; for HPC, &lt;em&gt;parallel programming frameworks/models&lt;/em&gt; to leverage them, and &lt;em&gt;energy efficiency&lt;/em&gt;. I’m also interested in everything that is performance-related, and I like to build systems that work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I offer Bachelor and Master&amp;rsquo;s theses, and I am happy to supervise Research Projects (&lt;a href=&#34;https://studiegids.vu.nl/EN/courses/2024-2025/XM_0129#/&#34;&gt;XM_0129&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://studiegids.vu.nl/en/Master/2024-2025/computer-science-joint-degree/XM_0130#/&#34;&gt;XM_130&lt;/a&gt;)  as well.
Below you can find a (non-exhaustive) list of potential project topics.
If you are interested in having a chat about the listed topics or proposing a new one, feel free to email me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;productively-program-spatial-accelerators&#34;&gt;Productively program Spatial Accelerators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spatial devices represent an avenue towards reducing the control and performance overhead of classical Load-Store Architecture (e.g., CPUs and GPUs).
In recent years, there has been a Cambrian explosion of spatial devices offered as Machine Learning Accelerators. While they come with software integration with popular Machine Learning frameworks, their potential in various scientific domains (e.g., computational
science, bioinformatics, graph processing) is still unexplored. The limited software support for non-ML workloads and
their steep learning curve make them inaccessible to non-experts. With my research, I want to address this gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects in this domain may regard:
Explore the capabilities of accessible (monetary-wise) Machine Learning Accelerators, such as AI engines in commodity processors, NPU, or Tenstorrent devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create benchmark, to understand their potential use in scientific applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port applications usually executed on other type of devices to spatial accelerators,  leveraging their unique characteristics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide frameworks, tools, and libraries to facilitate the development of applications targeting them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;high-performance-computing&#34;&gt;High-Performance Computing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the scale of computing systems increasing, we still have plenty of room to improve the performance of applications running on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this domain, there could be several projects on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accelerating applications on CPU/GPU-based systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benchmark new computing systems or solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop models to understand (and optimize) their behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sustainable-computing&#34;&gt;Sustainable Computing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, researchers and companies have started to be concerned about the environmental footprint of computing systems.
In the group, we have a successful history in building simulators for complex ecosystems such as data centers, and we are now investigating how
to consider sustainability, not just performance, as a first-class citizen in their design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this area, I am interested in topics such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modeling the interaction between different computing devices in heterogeneous systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;understanding power/sustainability and performance trade-off that might appear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developing carbon-aware scheduling algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
