<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FPGA | Tiziano De Matteis</title>
    <link>/tags/fpga/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/fpga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>FPGA</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>FPGA</title>
      <link>/tags/fpga/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMI</title>
      <link>/software/smi-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/software/smi-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- &lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; width=&#34;128&#34; height=&#34;128&#34; src=&#34;/img/fblas_logo.png&#34;&gt;/--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streaming Message Interface&lt;/strong&gt; is a a distributed memory HLS programming model for &lt;strong&gt;FPGAs&lt;/strong&gt; that provides
the convenience of message passing for HLS-programmed hardware devices. Instead of bulk transmission, typical of message passing model,
with SMI messages are &lt;strong&gt;streamed&lt;/strong&gt; across the network during computation, allowing communication to be seamlessly integrated into pipelined designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This repository contains an high-level synthesis implementation of SMI targeting OpenCL and Intel FPGAs, and all the
applications used for the evaluation perfomed in the paper: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Streaming Message Interface: High-Performance Distributed Memory
Programming on Reconfigurable Hardware&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, Tiziano De Matteis, Johannes de Fine Licht, Jakub Beránek, and Torsten Hofler. To appear in Proceedings of the International Conference for High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis, 2019 (SC 2019).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spcl/SMI/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;project webpace&lt;/a&gt; and to the paper for a reference on how to use SMI for your own distributed FPGA programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FBLAS</title>
      <link>/software/fblas-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/software/fblas-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- &lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; width=&#34;128&#34; height=&#34;128&#34; src=&#34;/img/fblas_logo.png&#34;&gt;/--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FBLAS&lt;/strong&gt; is a porting of the BLAS numerical library (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netlib.org/blas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.netlib.org/blas/&lt;/a&gt;) for Intel FPGA platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FBLAS provides two layers of abstraction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HLS modules&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be integrated into existing hardware designs. They implement BLAS routines (&lt;code&gt;DOT&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;GEMV&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;GEMM&lt;/code&gt;, etc.). Modules have been designed with compute performance in mind, exploiting the spatial parallelism and fast on-chip memory on FPGAs and have a streaming interface: data is received and produced using channels. In this way, they can be composed and communicate using on-chip resources rather than off-chip device RAM;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;a high-level &lt;strong&gt;Host API&lt;/strong&gt; conforming to the classical BLAS interface that allows the user to invoke routines directly from a host program. No prior knowledge on FPGA architecture and/or tools is needed. The user writes a standard OpenCL program: she is responsible to transferring data to and from
the device, she can invoke the desired FBLAS routines working on the FPGA memory, and then she copies back the result from the device.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further information on how to use the library, please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spcl/FBLAS/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
